1-17.
Exodus chapter 20 and we're going to
pick it up at verse
1. We're going to read 1-1 17. Exodus 20
1-17. Okay, brother Bruce, go ahead and
read. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which had
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shall
have no other gods before me. Thou shall
not make unto thee any greater image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth. Thou shall not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visit iniquity of the fathers, upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation, and them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto a thousand of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou should not take the name of the
Lord thy God in vain. For the Lord will
not hold him guiltless that taketh his
name in vain. Remember that Sabbath day
to keep it holy. Six days sh thou labor
and do all thy work. But the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou should not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that was within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in their ear is, and rested the seventh
day. Wherefore the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day, and hollowed it. Honor thy
father and thy mother, that thy days may
be long upon the land, which the Lord
thy God giveth thee. Thou shall not
kill. Thou shall not commit adultery.
Thou shall not steal. Thou shall not
bear false witness against thy neighbor.
Thou shall not covet thy neighbor's
house. Thou shall not coveret thy
neighbor's wife, nor his man's servant,
nor his maid servant, nor his ox, nor
his ass, nor anything that is thy
neighbor. And now we're going to read
Ecclesiastes
12 and we're going to read verses 13 and
14. Ecclesiastes 12
13 and 14. Okay, brother Bruce, go
ahead.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of man. For God should bring every work
into judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
>> And now we're going to go to Revelation
chap 22 and we're going to read verses
14 and 15. Revelation 22
verses 14 and 15.
Okay, brother Bruce, when you get it, go
ahead. Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they may have right to
the tree of life and may enter in
through the gates and to the city. For
without dogs and sulterers and
mongers and murderers and idolattors and
whosoever loveth in making alive. We
like to thank the Lord for the reading
of the law.
>> We like to welcome everyone here to the
Israel of God Bible study class here in
Buffalo, New York. I'm your teacher
today, Brother Harold. And reading today
is Buffalo's own, Brother Bruce.
And we'd like to welcome everyone here
to the Israel of God Buffalo. And it's
good to be here on the Lord's holy
Sabbath day. And without further ado,
we're going to get right into the
lesson. Today's lesson is the
destruction and restoration of Israel.
The destruction and restoration of
Israel. reason why we do a lesson like
this because people Israel's the one
that the one scattered here in this
hemisphere is known as Africanameans or
whatever name they want to call us
and we out here blaming all the other
nations but we haven't got right with
our God and that's the thing we going to
deal with today because it be because of
sin is why we sitting over here in
America instead of over there in the
land where we supposed to be. In fact,
the Lord when he delivered Israel out of
Egypt, he set before the contract.
He laid out the the thing. They got
married in the wilderness before they
even got in the land. He set out the
parameters. Look, I'm y'all going to
marry me, but this is the thing. You got
to keep my commandments. And if you
don't keep them, then he laid out what's
going to happen to your sons and
daughters. And look, Israel didn't
listen. So that's why we here scattered
all over the the world. And we going to
get right into this. We're going to
start this in Deuteronomy chapter 28.
Deuteronomy chapter 28. And we're going
to pick it up at verse one. Because the
Lord laid out, he set before Israel life
and death,
>> good and evil. And he said, "Choose life
and live."
And not only was there physical
Israelites there, there was strangers
among them.
Because those who all that believed,
they put the blood over the door post
and they was delivered. No matter what
nationality you came out of, Israel is
just a chosen priest of God. But his job
was to give the word to all the sons of
Adam. And that's what Israel lost sight
of. They lost sight of their God.
Therefore, the Lord punished Israel. And
he only left a remnant
that's really dealing with the truth.
That's why you got all this false
doctrine out here. Deuteronomy chapter
28. We're going to pick it up at verse
one. Deuteronomy 28 and one. When you
get it, Brother Bruce, go ahead.
And it shall come to pass, if thou shall
hearken diligently unto the voice of the
Lord thy God, to observe and do all his
commandments, which I command thee this
day, that the Lord thy God will set thee
on high above all nation of the earth.
>> You notice the key was diligently,
not slack. or when you feel like doing
it, you got to be diligent about this
thing.
>> That's what the key is because a lot of
us come to this word and when we came
out of that Sunday church, we went the
church all day when we was dealing with
the Sunday thing, but we get a a lesson
that's over an hour. We got a problem
with that.
>> And then when you sitting in them other
places, they didn't read you one
scripture,
>> right?
>> But he said what? diligently
could keep the commandments of the Lord.
Right? That's right.
>> Go ahead and read
>> verse two.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And all these blessings shall come on
thee.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And overtake thee.
>> If thou shall hearken unto the voice of
the Lord thy God.
>> See, man, could you imagine blessings
overtaking you?
>> That's something, ain't it, sir?
>> Go ahead and ring.
>> Bless thou be in the city, and blessed
thou be in the field. Now, if you found
yourself in the city, you would be
blessed. If you was in the field, you
would be blessed. We can't even imagine
that.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> One, blessed shall be the fruit of thy
body.
>> Your children going to be blessed. Go
ahead.
>> And the FRUIT OF THY GROUND.
>> EVERYTHING you plant going to be
blessed.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And the FRUIT OF THY CATTLE.
>> UHHUH. All your livestock going to be
blessed. Go ahead.
>> The increase of thy kind.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the flock of thy sheeps. If you had
kept the commandments of God, everything
you touched would have been blessed.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Because we serve the true and living
God.
>> Skip down to verse 12 and read.
>> The Lord shall open unto thee his good
treasure. Mhm.
>> the heaven to give the rain unto thy
land in its season, and to bless all the
work of thy hand, and thou shall lend
unto many nations, and thou shall not
bother.
>> We would have been the finances.
We would have been lending money to all
the other nations instead of going to
beg for somebody else to give us a loan.
>> Go ahead and ring.
>> And the Lord shall make thee the head
and not the tail.
>> Uh-huh. And thou shall be above only,
and thou shall not be beneath.
>> You going to be above only, not to boast
about anything, but to what? To honor
the Lord thy God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's what it's all about. Cuz God gets
all the glory. He is the one that give
you the rain when you need it. He gives
you everything. The air that you
breathing right now came from God,
people,
>> right? your health. You in your right
mind because God allowed you to have
your right mind.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Cuz if he take that away from you, you
ain't going to know what's going on.
>> That's right.
>> You finished 13.
>> The middle of verse 13.
>> Uh-huh.
>> If that thou hearken unto the
commandments of the Lord thy God, which
I command thee this day to observe and
to do them.
>> You notice the Lord is saying this
before Israel even went into the land.
This is in the wilderness.
>> He laying out this thing. Skip down to
verse 15 and read.
But it shall come to pass if thou will
not hearken unto the voice of the Lord
thy God, to observe to do all his
commandments and his statutes, which I
command thee this day, that all these
curses should come upon thee, and
overtake thee.
>> Now, this is the flip side. Now, if you
don't do the commandments, then all
these curses, they going to overtake
you. Go ahead.
>> Curse should thou be in the city. Curse
should thou be in the field.
>> So now, if you find yourself, you break
the commandments, now you going to be
cursed in the city. And if you in the
field, you going to be cursed. Go ahead.
>> Cursed shall be thy basket in that
store.
>> You ain't going to be able to save no
money.
>> That's right. going to be like a you
putting ho money in a hole your pocket
and it's just falling right to the
ground. Go ahead.
>> Verse 18. Curse shall be the fruit of
thy body.
>> Now your children going to be cursed. Go
ahead.
>> And the fruit of thy land.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the increase of thy kind and the
flocks of thy sheep.
>> Yeah. Now all things you touch is going
to be cursed if you break them
commandments. You read 18, right? Skip
down to verse 25 and read.
>> The Lord shall cause thee to be smitten
before thine enemies.
>> Thou shalt go out one way against them
and flee seven ways before them and
shall be removed into the all kingdoms
of the earth.
>> And you going to be what? Not migrate.
>> You're going to be what? Removed into
all kingdoms of the earth. That means
somebody going to take you there, right?
Yes, sir.
>> This is the word of God.
Skip down to verse 28 and read.
>> The Lord shall smite thee with madness
and blindness and astonishment apart.
>> Uh-huh. You going to be mad at everybody
and you're going to be astonished. How
come I can't get ahead? How come I'm the
last hired and the first fired?
>> That's right.
>> When it's layoffs, I'm always getting
laid off first.
>> Yes, sir.
>> These are the things that's going to
happen. but not keeping the commandments
of God. And Israel was his chosen
priest. So therefore, we did not keep
the commandments. So therefore, the Lord
said, "What? All these curses going to
come upon you and overtake you." Go
ahead and read.
>> And thou shall grope at noon day.
>> Uhhuh.
>> As the blind groweth in darkness, and
thou shall not prosper in thy ways. And
thou shalt be only oppressed and spoiled
ever more. And no man shall save thee.
>> You know what? Oppressed and then spoil,
people going to take advantage of you.
>> That's what Don't they come in your
community and take advantage of you?
>> That's right.
>> Your dollar don't circulate like other
people dollars do.
>> You paying somebody else.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read
>> verse 30. Thou shall betroth a wife and
another man shall li y'all watch them
movies.
>> Yes, sir.
>> About slavery and all that, right? Go
ahead and read.
>> Thou shall build a house and thou shall
not dwell there.
>> You going to build all these great
edififices and you ain't going to be
able to dwell in it. That's right. Go
ahead and read.
>> Thou shall plant a vineyard
>> and shall not gather the grapes thereof.
>> Uhhuh. Y'all heard of sharecropping,
right?
>> That's right. Yes, sir. you you would
deal with your whole crop all year and
then the person would say, "Look, you
just got enough to get by."
>> Yes, sir.
>> Skip down to verse 36 and read, "The
Lord shall bring thee and thy king,
which thou shalt set over thee unto a
nation which neither thou nor thy
fathers have known." Mhm.
>> And there shall And there shalt thou
serve other gods, wood and stone.
>> Wood and stone.
>> You going to worship all these guys that
worship what? People that worship wood
and stone.
You don't think you worshiping a stone?
Put them people out there all garbed up.
They go around a stone every year and
trample themselves to death every year.
>> That's right.
>> That is a stone. They claim that fell
from Jupiter.
>> Yes, sir.
>> These people, this is what And we
begging to get into this type of stuff.
>> I know
>> because the Lord called it and it's
going to happen.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read
>> 37. And thou shall become an
astonishment, A PROVERB, AND A by word
among all nations where the Lord shall
lead thee.
>> They call you every name but what?
Israel. Ain't that something? Yes, sir.
>> They going to call you every name but
Israel, which is God's name. Y'all know
all them different names they call you.
>> That's right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> This is the word of God, people. Skip
down to verse 41 and read.
>> Thou shall begat sons and daughters, but
thou shalt not enjoy them.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For they shall go into captivity.
>> Oh, you seen the dead? They go they
going to go, you know that one movie
with what was it? Kizzy and she couldn't
and they sold her kid.
>> That's right.
>> But now in the today since they took
that chatter slavery, now your sons and
daughters going to what? Prison house.
Yes, sir.
>> That's right.
>> And you ain't enjoying them because you
ain't taught them nothing.
>> People uh what about the kids?
>> But you were supposed to teach the kids
what? The commandments of God,
>> right?
>> That they might have a hope in God and
not forget the words of God, but what?
Keep his commandments.
>> Yes, sir.
You don't keep the commandments of God.
Guess what?
>> There's a prison laying for you.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> 43.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The stranger that is within thee.
>> Wait, excuse me. 42.
>> 42.
>> All thy trees and fruits of thy land
should be locust consumed.
The stranger that is within thee should
get up above thee very high, and thou
shall come down very low. So when Israel
came out of Egypt, it was a mixed
multitude, right? Yes, sir.
>> That came out of Egypt according to
Exodus 12. Right.
>> Right.
>> He said that stranger that's among you
going to come, you going to come down
very low and the stranger is going to
come up high.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> 44. He shall lend to thee.
>> He going to lend to you
>> and thou shall not lend to him.
>> And you ain't going to lend to him. But
if you had kept the commandments, it
would have been vice versa or what?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read. He shall be the handh
and thou shall be the tail
>> and you going to be on the bottom.
>> Even when you see the immigration,
immigration coming here, America is an
example, a
>> they come over here, they start prosper,
they get the stores and start pro and
you get mad at them.
>> That's right.
>> Why they why they got all the stores?
>> Cuz what the book don't lie. No matter
what you want to um what what you want
to you don't want to hear it. You want
to claim somebody else wrote it, right?
>> But can you stop it?
>> You can't stop it, can you? Because it's
the word of God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You can escape these things for a
little. The Lord said he'd be a little
sanctuary to you for a minute,
>> but the the overall picture is it ain't
going to look good.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read. Moreover, all these
curses should come upon thee, and shall
pursue thee, overtake thee,
>> till thou be destroyed. And
>> they going to overtake you. Go ahead.
>> Because thou hearkenest not unto the
voice of the Lord thy God,
>> to keep his commandments and his
statutes which he commanded thee.
>> Why would the Lord do this? Because
Israel is his priest. And he told you,
Israel, only have I known of all the
families of the earth. Therefore, I'm
going to punish you for what? all your
iniquities.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That means you ain't going to get away
with nothing.
>> That's right.
>> You going to get punished more than the
other nations because you supposed to
know better.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Your biggest
culprit or the one that keep you in
trouble is your shepherd because he lied
to you all the time telling you ain't
nothing, you ain't come from nothing,
you ain't going nowhere.
>> That's right.
>> And he teaches you that and he don't
teach you God commandments.
Therefore, you are in trouble.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read
>> verse 46. Uhhuh. And they shall be upon
thee for a sign of
>> What do a sign do?
>> The sign points to something, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> We We on Fair Street, ain't we? Yeah.
>> That's the sign that points where the
Israel of God is at, right?
>> Kimmore and Fairbanks.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read. And they shall be
upon thee for a sign and for a wonder
and upon thy seed forever.
>> They going to be on you because until
the Lord deliver you because you didn't.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Listen, read 47.
>> Because thou servest not the Lord thy
God. With joyfulness.
>> With what? With joyfulness. Go ahead.
>> And with gladness of heart.
>> With gladness of heart. Man, I got to go
in there and keep that Sabbath.
>> That's right. That's how they man.
>> I'm a witness.
>> You know, it ain't no joyous occasion
for you.
>> YOU SHOULD BE GLAD to get in here. You
keep the Sabbath day because that's what
you can read out of the Bible, people.
That's right. That's right.
>> You can't read that other stuff.
>> They come in there. You know, the book
say
>> you should keep the Lord thy God, and on
the seventh day, you shall have a holy
convocation. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You can read that, can't you?
>> Exactly.
>> You can't read that other stuff. But
these people diligent about that, ain't
they?
>> Yes, they are.
>> Why can't you be diligent about
something you can read?
>> Praise the Lord.
>> That's all I'm saying.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> For the abundance of all things.
>> For the what? Abundance of all things.
Cuz God give you whatever you got in
your pocket, the air you breathe in, the
house you live in, sir.
>> Everything came from God, people.
>> That's right.
>> He You got to give him the glory.
>> Drop that word.
>> You got to give it to him.
>> Yes, sir. and you better serve him like
he did it gave it to you.
>> Skip down to verse 63 and read.
>> And it shall come to pass that as the
Lord rejoiced over you to do you good
>> and to multiply you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> So the Lord will rejoice over you TO
DESTROY YOU.
>> WAIT A MINUTE. God would do that,
Brother Bruce.
>> Yes. That's what the book said.
>> Go ahead.
>> And to bring you to north.
>> Uh-huh. And ye shall be plucked from off
the land whether thou goest to possess
it.
>> You ain't going to migrate. You going to
be plucked. Yes, sir.
>> That means somebody going to pull you up
and take you somewhere.
>> Go ahead.
>> And the Lord should scatter thee among a
people from the one end of the earth,
even unto the other.
>> And there thou shall serve other God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Which neither thou nor thy father have
known, even wood and stone. Your fathers
didn't know about Easter, people.
>> That's right.
>> Your fathers didn't know about
Christmas,
>> right?
>> That's somebody else's God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's not the God of Israel.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> And among these nations shall thou find
no ease.
>> You ain't going to find no ease. This
ain't going to be easy.
>> That's right.
>> It's not easy here in America.
>> That's right. No, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Neither shall the SOUL OF THY FOOT have
rest.
>> Uhhuh. You scared of everything.
>> Yes, sir. You don't have no rest. You
either scared of somebody that look like
you or some other nation.
>> Exactly.
>> And they and your life don't mean
nothing.
>> That's That's correct.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> But the Lord should give thee
>> there a trembling heart.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And fell inh.
>> That's why we seen the blues better than
anybody else. Yes, sir.
>> Teach.
>> Because we got a sour heart. We got a
sad story about anything, don't we?
>> That's right. Teach that truth, brother.
Go ahead and read.
>> And thy life shall hang in doubt uh
before theeuh and thou shall fear day
and night and shall have none assurance
of thy life.
>> Go look and see who likely to die of a
homicide, people.
>> That's right.
>> Look in the books.
>> Yes, sir. No, you know,
>> look who got more diseases than anybody
else. Diabetes, heart disease.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Keep reading, man.
>> 67.
>> Uhhuh. And in the morning thou sh say
with God it were ease.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And at evening thou sh say with God it
were more.
>> You ain't going to be safe whether is
daytime or night time.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> For the fear of thine heart wherewith
thou shall fear
>> and for the sight of thine eyes which
thou shalt see.
>> And the
>> Go ahead.
>> 68. And the Lord shall bring thee to
Egypt again with ships.
>> Uh-huh. Egypt is our first captivity.
Right. Yes sir. And he said, "You ain't
going back into Egypt." Right.
>> So this is captivity here. Yes, sir.
>> He's talking about you going to go into
Egypt this time by what?
>> Ships.
>> Ships. Go ahead.
>> By the way, WHEREOF I SPAKE unto thee.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Thou shall see it no more again.
>> And there ye shall be sold unto your
enemies for bonds men and bonds women,
and no man shall buy you.
>> Who do this fit?
>> Israel. If this is real, cuz this going
to be a sign, right?
>> Yes, sir. You going to go into captivity
by ships. Remember this was called
before Israel even went into the land.
They was in the wilderness. Yes, sir.
>> And that was the thing. This was the
curse side of it. The blessing was that
if you kept the commandments, you would
be off top.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You would be lon all the other nations.
Everything you touch would have been
blessed. But since we didn't listen, we
got the curses. Let's let's see Daniel
confirm this. Daniel chapter 9 because
he was in the captivity too.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Daniel chapter 9, we're going to pick it
up at verse 8. Daniel chapter 9 and
we're going to pick it up at verse 8.
See, this is the Bible. See, people
think it's a joke. It ain't no joke.
>> You just got to obey the word of God and
the Lord going to fix this thing.
Eventually, he going to fix it. But you
got to be make sure you on the right
side so you can enjoy the blessing when
it come.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Daniel chapter 9, we going to pick it up
at verse 8. And then we going to skip to
verse 11. Go ahead and read.
>> Oh Lord, to us belong confusion of faith
to our kings, to our princes, and to our
fathers because we have sinned against
thee.
>> Now Daniel is what? Confessing here.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He confessing to the Lord. Skip down to
verse 11 and read. Yay, all Israel have
transgressed thy law.
>> You have transgressed mean broken the
law. And sin is a transgression of the
law. Go ahead.
>> Even by departing that they might not
obey thy voice. Therefore, the curse is
poured upon us.
>> Wait. Therefore, the curse is poured
upon us. That's
>> right.
>> Now, this what people saying. You go
ahead and curse. I know
>> you calling one of the Lord's servants a
liar. You calling the Lord a liar
because he got this from the
>> Daniel got it from the Lord.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> In the oath that is written in the law
of Moses, the servant of God because we
have sinned against him.
>> Because what? We have sinned against
him. Go ahead. Verse 12. And he has
confirmed his words which he spake
against us and against our judges that
judged us by bringing upon us a great
evil.
>> He that bringeth upon what? This great
>> Go ahead.
>> For under the whole heaven has not been
done as has been done upon Jerusalem.
>> Ain't that something? Ain't no other
nation went into captivity by ships,
people.
>> That's right. No other nation.
You read 13.
>> No.
>> Read 13.
>> As it is written, the law of Moses, all
this evil is come upon us. Yet make we
not our prayer before the Lord our God,
that we might turn from our iniquities
and understand thy truth.
>> And what the truth is, all the
commandments of God is true.
>> Yes, sir. And he said all we have to do
even if we even in this captivity if we
would turn to the Lord and acknowledge
our iniquities. We don't think nothing
wrong. We won't blame everybody else.
>> That's right.
>> Get your house in order.
>> Didn't he always tell you get the beam
out of your eye before you get the mo
out of somebody else? Yes, sir.
>> We want to blame every other nation, but
we haven't straightened it out with our
God. That's right.
>> Straighten it out with the God. Start by
keeping his Sabbath day.
>> Yes, sir. his feast days,
>> his dietary law.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Deuteronomy 32, we're going to pick it
up at verse 8.
>> We're going to eventually get to the new
book. Deuteronomy 32, we're going to
pick it up at verse 8. We're going to
read 8 to 10.
Deuteronomy 32 and verse 8.
Go ahead and read. When the Most High
divided to the nations the inheritance,
when he separated the sons of Adam,
>> he set the bounds of the people
according to the number of the children
of Israel.
>> He said it according to what? The number
of the children of Israel. How many?
>> 12.
>> 12. Right. Then Jacob had 12 sons.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Don't you got 12 hours a day and 12
hours of what? Night. Yes, sir.
>> You got 12 months of the year, don't
you?
Go ahead and read nine. For the Lord
port for the Lord portion is his people
Jacob is the lot of his inheritance.
>> Go ahead.
>> He found him in a desert land and in the
waist harrow and wilderness.
>> He led him about. He instructed him. He
kept him as the apple of his eye.
>> What he how do he instruct them? By the
commandments. That is your guide.
>> Go ahead and read. Um,
>> oh, skip down to 15. Skip down to 15.
But what what happened? Go ahead and
read.
>> But Jezeron
waxed and kicked.
>> Jeson is Israel. He said, "But Jezon
waxed fat and what? Kick." Cuz you got
you prospered and you thought you was
the one that did it and not the Lord.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Thou waxing fat. Thou grown thick.
>> Thou covered with fatness.
>> Uhhuh. Then he forsook God which made
him enlighten esteemed the rock of his
salvation.
>> Who was the rock of his salvation?
>> Jesus.
>> Yes sir.
>> Before he was manifest in the flesh.
>> You forgot about the God that delivered
you out of Egypt. Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> They provoked him to jealousy with
strange gods.
>> Wait a minute. With strange gods.
>> Yes, sir. That's why people walking
around here talking about they they
Jewish
>> with a so-called star around they neck.
>> That's right.
>> That's the star for them people.
>> Yes, sir.
>> They ain't The Lord ain't had no star.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> They provoked him to jealousy with
strange God
>> with abominations provoked provoked they
him to anger.
>> Go ahead.
>> THEY SACRIFICE UN DEVILS NOT to God.
Uh-huh.
>> To gods whom they knew not. To new gods
that came newly up, whom your fathers
feared not.
>> Uh-huh. To new god. That's the new we in
these last day. The new gods is Easter
and Christmas.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> OF THE ROCK THAT BEGAT THEM. I mean, of
the rock that begat thee, thou are
unmindful and has forgotten God that
formed you.
>> How did you forget the God that formed
you? By breaking his commands. Yes,
>> sir.
>> Go ahead and read. And when the Lord saw
it, he abhored.
>> He He what? Ah whoroed them. Yhoord, he
hated them.
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead.
>> Because the provoking of his sons and of
his daughters.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he said, "I will hide my faith from
them."
>> I will see what their end shall be.
>> He said, "Now I'm going to let you go.
I'mma let them all take advantage of
you. I'mma hide my face from you and
I'mma see what your end going to be." Go
ahead.
I will see what their end shall be. For
they are a very forward generation,
children in whom is no faith. But
>> now let me I looked up the word forward.
Look listen to what this say. Forward.
Forward.
>> Forward.
>> Forward. Right.
>> Yes sir.
>> Forward.
>> Willingly contrary stubbornly
disobedient. Yes sir.
>> Or difficult to manage.
It is an older somewhat library word
used to describe someone that with who
does the exact opposite of what they are
asked.
>> Ain't that something?
>> Yes sir.
>> Argues to be difficult.
>> Think about that.
>> When you start listening to that, that's
why the Lord said he what? He hated
that.
>> That's right.
>> And people, you know, you know the
Sabbath day, the seventh day. Oh no,
man. It's the first day of the week.
>> No, right.
>> The Lord did away with that when he died
on the cross.
>> That's right.
>> Read that to me.
>> They can't read it.
>> No, sir.
>> Cuz they fro.
>> Yes.
>> Argues to be difficult to do the exact
opposite of what the Lord told them to
do.
>> That's right.
>> Now, y'all got an idea of that, right?
Yes, sir.
>> By looking up that word.
>> That's right.
>> You finished what verse was that?
>> That was verse 20.
20. Yeah, we ready.
>> Skip down to 23. I'm I'm losing. Go
ahead. Read read 23. All right.
>> I will heap mischief upon them. I will
spend mine arrows. I will spend my
arrows upon them.
>> And he said, I'm going to spend my
arrows upon them. This the Lord speaking
to the people. You skip down to verse
26. It ain't like the Lord just spare.
He use other nations to spin arrows upon
you people. Skip down to verse 26.
Go ahead.
>> I said I will scatter them into corners.
Uhhuh.
>> I will make the the remembrance of them
to cease from among men.
>> I'mma make what? The remembrance of them
to cease from what? Among men.
>> Now all you think you are is
Africanamean.
>> Yes.
>> Your hometown is Mississippi or
Virginia.
You don't know where you came from,
where you going, or nothing. Reason why?
Because you broke the commandments of
God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> The only written history that's left of
you
>> is this.
>> That's it.
This is the only history that's left of
you.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> And if you don't read it, that's why
everybody kicking against it, saying,
"Oh, this is wrong. That's wrong."
Because they trying to kill your whole
people.
>> That's right.
>> They trying to say, "You ain't nothing.
You ain't come from nowhere. You ain't
going nowhere.
>> Right.
>> That's why you better hold on to this
book. That's all that's record of you
people.
>> Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
>> Jud Jeremiah 15. Jeremiah 15.
That's why when somebody bring me some
garbage, hey, it go in one ear and out
the other. I see you at the
resurrection.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And I'm going to try to keep the
commandments of God. so I can make it
in.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> Cuz that stuff on the internet is all
polluted.
>> That's right.
>> Jeremiah 15, we're going to pick it up
at verse one. Go ahead and read.
>> Then said the Lord unto me. Though Moses
and Samuel stood before me, yet my mind
could not be toward this people.
>> Cast them out of my sight and let them
go forward. And when he talk about
casting him out of his sight, he tell
you in dut Deuteronomy chapter 11, he
said his eyes and ears is always toward
Jerusalem. Right.
>> So if he cast you out of that land, he
just cast you what? Out of his sight.
>> Yes, sir. That's right.
>> And he said the land going to be laid
desolate.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That mean it's going to be empty. Even
though another people occupy it, the
ones that supposed to be there is not
there.
>> That's right.
>> But to the Lord, it's empty.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read
>> verse two. And it shall come to pass, if
they say unto thee, whether shall we go
forth, then thou shall tell them, thus
said the Lord, such as are for death to
death, and such as for the sword to the
sword, and such are for the famine to
the famine, and such as for and such as
are for the captivity to the captivity.
He got He finally got to us on that
captivity side, right? We part of that
captivity.
>> Go ahead and read. And I will appoint
over them four kinds, said the Lord. The
sword to slay and the dogs to tear and
the fowls of the heaven and the beast of
the earth to devour and destroy.
>> Ain't that song?
>> Yes, sir.
>> So no matter where you go, all these
things going to happen to you as a
people.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read. and I will cause them
to be removed into all kingdoms of the
earth.
>> Man, he he testifying what Moses said,
right?
>> And Jeremiah was in the captivity under
the Babylonian captivity. Right.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Because of Manasse, the son of Hezekiah,
king of Judah, for that which he did in
Jerusalem.
>> Go see what Manasseh did. He did all
this wickedness before the Lord. You go
to the kings on your own and see what
Manasseh did. And you would be like,
"Whoa."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And then this brother, he tried to
repent at the end.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Five. For who shall have pity upon thee,
oh Jerusalem? Or who shall be thee? Or
who shall go aside to ask how thou
doest?
>> Thou hast forsaken me, said the Lord.
Thou art gone backwards. Therefore will
I stretch out my hand against thee, and
destroy thee. I am weary with
repentance.
>> Uhhuh. Because the Lord would deliver
Israel. Yes sir.
>> Then he would send somebody to deliver
them.
>> Yes sir.
>> The L and then they say they repent.
Right. He would send somebody to
deliver. He would deliver them. Then
they would few years later they would go
back and do
>> break God's commandment. He send
somebody else to deliver them and they
would go back to breaking the
commandments of God. We the only nation
that would backslid.
>> Yes sir. because we had the commandments
of God.
>> Now, let's go and see when Jesus came on
the scene. Let's go to Luke chapter 19.
Luke chapter 19. Because the Lord
allowed Ezra and Nehemiah to go back to
build the temple.
And then
let's see what happened cuz Jesus came
back in the flesh. And let's see what he
said about the city cuz he wept over
Jerusalem. Luke 19, we're going to pick
it up at verse 41. Luke 19 and 41.
Cuz Jesus came to die for our sins. And
then he went back on the right hand of
the father. But before he died, let's
see what he said about Jerusalem. Luke
19 and verse 41. What does it say?
>> And when he was come near, he beheld the
city and wept over it.
>> He wept over the city. He leapt over
Jerusalem
>> because he knew after his death, he was
going to send the Romans in.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Saying, "If thou hadest known even thou
at least in this thy day the things
which belong unto thy peace, but now
they are hid from thine eyes."
>> You see, now they hid from you. Go
ahead.
For the day shall come upon thee, that
thine enemy shall cast a trench about
thee, and compass thee round, and keep
thee in all, keep thee in on every side.
>> Now you go to history of 70 AD, the
Romans built a trench around Jerusalem,
sir,
>> and they crucify everybody that would
try to get in and those who tried to get
out. And it was they say history say
what the crosses would not bear was 500
a day.
>> That's right.
>> This is what happened after the death of
Jesus.
>> Not too long after in 70 AD. Jesus died
about what? 30
>> Yeah. 33.
>> 30 30 AD. But 70 AD is when this took
place
>> cuz he was calling it. Now let's go to
Luke chapter 21.
>> 44.
>> Oh 44. Okay. and shall lay thee even
with the ground, and thy children within
thee, and they shall not leave in thee
one stone upon another, because thou
knewest not the time of thy visitation.
>> And that temple was destroyed, and it
wasn't left one stone upon another.
Now, let's go to Luke 21.
Luke 21. And we're going to pick it up
at verse 20. Luke 21 and verse
20.
He going to talk about this again. Now
he going to get a little more intricate
about it.
Luke 21 and verse 20. We're going to
read 20 to 24 and let's see what it say.
Brother Bruce
Luke 21 and 20.
>> Yes.
Go ahead and read.
And when ye shall see Jerusalem
compassed with armies, then know that
the the desolation thereof is nigh.
>> Know that what? The destruction is nigh.
Go ahead and read.
>> Then let them which are in Judea flee to
the mountains, and let them which are in
the midst of it depart out, and let not
them that are in the countries enter
therein, too. Uh-huh.
>> For these be the days of vengeance, and
all things which are written may be
fulfilled.
>> And all things that are written by who?
Moses.
>> That may be what? Fulfilled. Cuz Moses
said, "Look, you going to be in the
captivity by ships and all that, right?"
Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> But warn to them that are with child and
to them that give suck in those days.
For there shall be great distress in the
land and wrath upon this people.
>> Uh-huh. Because they going to be
crucifying
500 people a day.
>> Go ahead and read 24. And they shall
fall by the edge of the sword
>> and shall be led away captives into all
nations. And Jerusalem shall be trotten
down of the Gentiles until the times of
the Gentiles be fulfilled. under there
the times of the Gentile rulership be
fulfilled. Who are the Gentiles?
Europeans.
Until they that be fulfilled until their
time is up, sir.
>> Cuz the Lord allowed all all these
different peoples to rule all three sons
of the sons of Noah. Ham rule first.
>> That's what we call what? Africans,
right?
>> That's right. Then you had Shemetic
tribes rule, right? David and Solomon,
Saul, David, Solomon. And now we are
ruling in these last days.
>> Yes, sir.
>> This is what's going to happen. And he
said until they times of the Gentiles be
fulfilled. Once they time is up, then
going to be the coming of the Lord. Yes,
sir.
>> We read uh verse 24, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, we going to move on. Let's go to
Psalm 44.
Psalm 44. And we're going to pick it up
at verse 1. Psalm 44 and verse one.
We're going to read 1 to two and then we
going to skip.
Okay. Go ahead. We have heard with our
ears, oh God, our fathers have told us
what work thou didest in their days, in
the times of old.
>> How thou didest drive out the heathen
with thy hand, and planted them, how
thou didest afflict the people, and cast
them out.
>> Uh-huh. Now, skip down to verse nine and
read.
>> But thou has cast off and put us to
shame. He said, "Now you done cast off
and put us to shame." Go ahead.
>> And goest not forth with our army.
>> Now the Lord ain't with you cuz the Lord
is the one that used to fight our
battles. Didn't
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> But thou hast cast off and put us to
shame and go not forth with our armies.
Verse 10. Thou maketh us to turn back
from the enemy,
>> and they which hate us spoiled for
themselves.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Thou hast given us like sheep appointed
for meat.
>> Uh-huh. Now you given us a black sheep
appointed for me. Go ahead.
>> And has scattered us among the heathen.
>> And you have scattered us among the
heathen. Heathen means nations. Now you
scattered among the nations.
>> Go ahead.
>> Verse 12. Thou sellest thy people for
not
>> and do not increase thy wealth by their
price.
>> Uh-huh. Who sell the people for no?
>> It was the Lord.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read. Thou make us a
reproach to our neighbors, a scorn, and
a derision to them that are round about
us.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thou make us a by word among the
heathen.
>> Now y'all make us, you make us what? A
by word among the heathen. They call you
every name but your real name. Yes, sir.
>> Which is Israel.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> A shaking of the head among the people.
>> Now, people just shake their head. Man,
why these people can't get it together?
>> Because what? They don't They won't turn
to their God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> See, people love to quote to you, "If
the Lord is for you, who can be against
you?"
>> That's right.
>> But if the Lord ain't for you,
everybody's against you.
>> That's right.
>> You don't look at that side because
people done took their reasoning out.
They what critical thinking out of it.
>> That's right.
>> So the Lord ain't with you. Everybody is
against you.
>> That's right.
That's right. It's proven.
>> Let's go to Zechariah chapter 11.
Zechariah chapter 11.
>> Zechariah 11 and we're going to pick it
up at verse 1.
>> See, we just reading the bad news now.
There's some good news coming.
>> Oh yes, sir.
>> There's some great news coming.
Zechariah 11 and we're going to pick it
up at verse one. We're going to read 1
to5. What it say? Open thy doors, oh
Lebanon, that the fire may devour thy
cedars.
>> Uhhuh.
>> How fur tree for the cedars is fallen.
>> Uhhuh. He using an analogy like trees,
but he talking about Israel here. Go
ahead and read.
>> Because the mighty are spoil how, oh ye
oaks of Bashan, for the forest of the
vintage is come down.
>> So the Lord speak in all kinds of
different ways. So you can get this
thing no matter what you in your
understanding. Yes, sir. Go ahead and
read.
>> There is a voice of the howling of the
shepherds, for their glory is spoiled.
>> A voice of the roaring of young lions,
for the pride of Jordan is spoiled.
>> Thus said the Lord my God, feed the
flock of the slaughter.
>> He said, what? Feed the flock of the
slaughter.
>> What? Go ahead.
>> Five. Whose possessors slay them and
hold themselves not guilty.
>> Ain't that something? the your
possessors, wherever you cap your
captive to, they gonna slay you and they
gonna what? Hold themselves not guilty.
Ain't that what's going on? You likely
to get shot in the street by somebody,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> And they don't even feel bad about it.
>> Go ahead and read it.
>> And they that sell them say, "Blessed be
the Lord, for I am rich."
>> And they use you to get rich. Yes, sir.
>> That's how these nations got rich.
United States got rich because of all
that free labor.
>> That's how they got then your overhead
is your your labor, right? Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And their own shepherds pity them not.
>> Who is the shepherds? Your preachers
pity you not because they don't they you
they about their money.
>> Yes, sir. They love that you in this bad
condition so they can hire keep
hollering racism.
Get right with your God people
>> and the Lord would change the he say if
you right with him he make even his
enemies to be have favor with you.
>> Yes sir.
>> Ain't that what the scripture say?
>> Try it. Cuz I done tried it.
>> People really tried to hurt me even on
when I was on the job. Guess what? The
Lord flipped that thing.
>> Yes, sir. Praise the Lord.
>> Because I held on to God, people.
>> That's right.
>> And I watched people go to the grave,
man, trying to mess with me.
>> That's a fact.
>> And I I was scared. I was shook up cuz I
don't want to see nobody do go get hurt.
>> Heads up.
>> And I said, man, that's why I'mma hang
on to the God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Cuz I ain't going to cross this guy,
people. That's right. He is dangerous.
But if he on your side, can't nobody be
against you because
>> that's just the way it is. Let's go on.
Let's go to Isaiah chapter 42.
Isaiah 42.
We're going to pick it up at verse 18. I
ain't saying I'm nobody. I just say I'm
serve the Lord. I'm trying to be real
humble about this thing.
>> Trust me, he is he is has a
>> contrite and humble spirit and I'm
trying to have that also.
>> Yes, sir. Isaiah 42 and we're going to
pick it up at verse 18.
That's why we supposed to be the
humblest people on the planet. Yes, sir.
>> Cuz our God is of a contrite humble
spirit.
>> That's right. Praise the Lord.
>> He said, "Come to me for my yoke is easy
and my burden is light."
>> That's right.
>> Isaiah 42, we going to pick it up at
verse 18. 18 to 25. What does it say?
>> Hear ye deaf and look ye blind that you
may see.
>> Who is deaf? He He's talking about the
spiritual death and the spiritual blind.
>> Go ahead.
>> Who who is blind but my servant.
>> Uhhuh. Why? Why did you become blind
spiritually? Because you didn't keep the
commandments of God. Yes, sir.
>> And the commandments is a light and a
lamp according to Proverbs. Ain't it?
Yes, sir.
>> That's why you don't see things
>> you're supposed to see spiritually
because you don't want to keep the
commandments.
>> Go ahead and read. or death as my
messenger that I sent.
>> Uh-huh. Cuz Israel was supposed to be
the messenger.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Who is blind as he that is perfect?
>> You can't add nothing to perfection.
>> That's right.
>> You know everything.
>> Man, I used to think I knew a little
bit.
>> I had decent grades in school and
everything. And man, I soon as I was ran
into that book,
>> man, I ain't know nothing. I couldn't
even count the three. I couldn't get
three days or three nights from Good
Friday to Good Easter Sunday. Right.
>> Right.
>> Man, I humbled myself. I got no tapes.
>> Brother Bony will tell you cuz I gave
them tapes to him after I had them.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> I would ride in the car and just be
listening to the word of God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I didn't know the Lord was preparing me
to teach later. I didn't know that. God,
>> but I was like, man, I had to catch it
up.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And I ain't know nothing.
>> I was dumb as a rock. Look at you
>> when it cames to the word of God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And blind as the Lord's servant.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Seeing many things, but thou observest
not.
>> You see the things, but you don't
observe them. Go ahead.
>> Opening the ears.
>> Uh-huh.
>> But he heareth not.
>> You open your ears, you don't hear
nothing. You like you just walking blind
and deaf. Go ahead and read.
>> The Lord is well pleased for his
righteousness sake.
>> Uh-huh. He will magnify the law and make
it honorable.
>> Who is going to magnify the law? Jesus.
Yes, sir.
>> He going to magnify it and make it
honorable cuz he's kept every single
word of God of the word of the law. Go
ahead.
>> Verse 22. But this is a people robbed
and spoiled.
>> Uhhuh.
>> There are all of them snared in whole.
>> And they are hid in prison houses.
>> They are hid in what?
>> Who make up a majority of the prison
population? per cap for amount of people
that's in in this country
>> is real.
>> Yes, sir.
>> No matter what nation we in, it's the
same results. That's right.
>> You go to China and you going to see a
lot of us in there.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Therefore, I pray and none delivereth.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For it spoil and none says restore
>> you. for they going to take advantage of
you and nobody says, "Hey, why y'all
give these people a break? Give them a
few dollars."
>> No, sir.
Go ahead.
>> Who among you will give ear to this?
>> Who going to give ear to this?
Who will hearken and hear for the time
to come?
>> The time is now. Who going to hear this?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Can't you see?
>> That's right.
>> That this is us.
Go ahead and read
>> verse 24. Who gave Jacob for a spoil and
Israel to the robbers?
>> Did not the Lord. He against whom we
have sinned.
>> No, it was somebody else, Bruce.
>> He against whom
is not the did not the Lord. He against
whom we have sinned.
>> The Lord is the one that did this.
>> That's right. because you didn't obey
and I told you I was gonna do this thing
and God cannot lie.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, he allowed these other people to
take advantage of you.
>> That's right.
>> So, that's why I ain't mad at nobody.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I'm trying to get myself right so when
the blessing come, I can get the
blessing.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Ain't no need of me taking this whooping
now and then get thrown in the lake of
fire, too. That's crazy.
>> I know. Right.
>> And you know what? Why this happened?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read. FOR THEY WOULD NOT
WALK in his ways.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Neither were they obedient unto his law.
>> They wouldn't walk in his ways and
wouldn't be obedient to the law. Verse
25, what does it say?
>> Therefore, he has poured upon him the
fury of his anger
>> in the strength of battle, and it has
set him on fire round about.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yet he knew not.
>> Yet he don't even know what's going on.
>> Go ahead.
>> And it burns him.
>> Uhhuh. Yet he laid it not too hard.
>> Never say, "Man, why this happening to
me?"
You don't even lay it to heart. I
remember I was seeking as a young kid
>> cuz I was like, my dad used to tell me
stories, you know, how how I was bad at
the job and how they treated, you know,
different people and all that. And this
brother used to work with him. And man,
I was like, as a kid, why? I kept asking
why. And then when I found out, I said,
"Oh, okay. This is why." Because we the
people of God, sir, and we sinned
against the Lord.
>> Therefore, he flipped the scale. Cuz we
all got hands, feet.
>> That's right.
>> If the Lord flipped this scale, you
can't change it.
>> That's right.
>> Cuz it's a spiritual thing.
>> Yes, sir.
>> It ain't got nothing to do with
physical.
>> That's why we ain't got no reason to be
mad at nobody.
>> That's right.
>> Angry.
>> Isaiah 51. We're going to pick it up at
verse 17.
Isaiah 51-17.
Let's look at some of the conditions
when you in this captivity. Let's see.
So Isaiah 51, we going to pick it up at
verse 17. And you tell me who this fit.
Go ahead and read.
>> Awake. Awake. Stand up, O Jerusalem,
which has drunk at the hand of the Lord
the cup of his fury.
>> You drunk at the hand of the Lord, the
cup of his fury. Go ahead. Thou hast
drunken the breads of the cup of tremlin
and rung them out.
>> Oh man, you drunken so much you have
rung it out. Go ahead and read.
>> There is none to guide her among all the
sons whom she has brought forth.
>> Neither is there any that taken her by
the hand of all the sons that she has
brought up.
>> Uh-huh.
>> These two things have come upon thee.
>> I mean, these two things have come unto
thee.
>> Who shall be sorry for thee? Who going
who going to s be sorry for? Who going
to plead your cause? Go ahead.
>> Desolation and destruction.
>> Uh-huh.
>> In the famine and the sword.
>> By whom shall I comfort thee?
>> Uh-huh.
>> Thy sons have fainted.
>> They lie at the head of all the streets.
>> Who hang on the street corners?
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Has a wild bull in the net.
>> And there's a wild bull in the net. You
scared to go in that store cuz them
brothers hanging on that corner
>> and you don't know what might happen to
you.
>> I done seen it happen. Sometime man they
be like I be scared sometime to go in
there and then I say them what's up man.
Then I ease up and go in the store.
I'm just saying.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> They are full of the fury of the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The rebuke of thy God. Why that fear
full of fear of the Lord? Because you
haven't taught them anything.
They don't think they going nowhere.
>> That's right.
>> They don't think they about nothing.
Therefore, they just angry
>> instead of teaching them the truth about
who they are and put down that gun and
pick up this sword of the spirit which
is the Bible.
>> And go out there and be fishes of men.
>> Yes, sir. instead of killers of men.
>> That's right.
>> Ain't that something?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's go to Deuteronomy chapter 30.
Deuteronomy chapter 30. We're going to
pick it up at verse one. Deuteronomy 30.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
one.
Go ahead and read.
And it shall come to pass when all these
things are come upon thee,
>> Uhhuh.
>> the blessing and the curse,
>> Uhhuh. which I have set before thee, and
thou shalt call them to mind among all
the nations, whether the Lord thy God
has driven thee.
>> Ain't that something? He took it to our
time and beyond.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Moses writing this thing.
>> That's right.
>> Before we was even in the land.
>> Go ahead.
>> And shall return unto the Lord thy God.
>> And you going to return unto the Lord
thy God.
>> And shall obey his voice according to
all that I command thee this day. Go
them same commandments.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Thou and thy children,
>> you and your children,
>> with all thine heart, and with all thy
soul.
>> And you going to serve him with all your
heart and all your soul. Go ahead.
>> That then the Lord thy God will turn thy
captivity.
>> Then he going to turn your captivity. Go
ahead.
>> And have compassion upon.
>> And he going to have compassion upon
you.
>> And will return and deliver thee from
all the nations.
>> Wait. He is going to return.
>> Yes, sir. And he going to gather you
from all the nations, whether he has
what?
>> Whether he had ga and gathered thee from
all the nations, whether the Lord thy
God has scattered you,
>> that he going to gather you from all the
nations where he have scattered you. Go
ahead and read.
>> If any of thine be driven out unto the
outmost parts of heaven,
>> Uh-huh. That's still the earth.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> From hence will the Lord thy God gather
thee?
>> Uhhuh. Because it's three heavens. And
the the the first heaven is the earth.
Yes sir.
>> Second heaven is everything above the
earth and beyond that is you got body of
water and then you got the where the
father and son dwell. If you be driven
to the outermost part of the earth, he
going to find you.
>> Yes sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And from this will he fetch thee.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And the Lord thy God will bring thee
into the land which thy father
possessed, and thou shall possess it.
>> And he will do thee good. And he going
to do you good
>> and multiply thee above thy fathers.
>> And he going to multiply you above thy
fathers. See, I ain't shooting. I'm
shooting to be ruling with Christ for a
thousand years. Praise the Lord.
>> I'm shooting for the big thing.
>> That's right. Shooting.
>> I want to run the earth with Christ.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For a thousand years.
>> I leave this for the other people that's
be left.
>> Yes, sir.
>> But I'm shooting for the honor road.
>> Praise the Lord. do uh Isaiah 61. I know
hope y'all shooting for the same thing.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Unsc don't have no power over.
>> Let it rub off.
>> Isaiah 61.
We going to pick it up.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I mean Isaiah 50. What? 61. 61.
>> Mhm.
>> And we going to pick it up at verse one.
Isaiah 61. Keep a marker in Isaiah cuz
we going to come right back to it after
we go to the next place. Isaiah 61.
We're going to read one and two and then
we gonna go to Luke. Isaiah 61. We're
going to pick it up at verse one. What?
>> The spirit of the Lord is upon me.
>> Because the Lord had anointed me to
preach good tidings unto the meek.
>> Uhhuh.
>> He has sent me to bind up the
brokenhearted
>> to proclaim liberty to the cap to the
captives and the opening of the prison
to them that are bound.
>> Wait a minute. to the opening of the
prisons, not only physically and
spiritually, too.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> To proclaim the acceptable year of the
Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> In the day of vengeance to our God, to
comfort all that mourn.
>> To comfort all that mourn. Let's see who
this was pointing to. Let's go to Luke
chapter 4. Keep a marker in Isaiah. We
coming back. Luke chapter 4. We're going
to pick it up at verse one. Luke chapter
4 and we're going to pick it up at verse
one. We're going to read one and two and
then we going to skip Luke chapter 4.
We're going to pick it up at verse one.
Isaiah prophesied about it. We're going
to see who this is pointing to.
And when you get it, Brother Bruce, go
ahead and read.
And Jesus being full of the Holy Ghost
returned from Jordan and was led by the
spirit into the wilderness.
>> You notice Jesus saved travels is like
Israel. Then what did he take Israel to?
The wilderness.
>> Jesus went to what? The wilderness.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Being 40 days tempted of the devil.
>> What? He was tempted 40 days. Right.
>> Then it take him what? How many days to
uh search out the land?
>> 40 years.
>> 40 days turned to 40 years.
>> It turned into what?
>> 40 years. Right.
>> 40 years.
>> Go ahead and read. Bony got that lesson
on 40. Go ahead and read. I'm just
pointing out some things. Go ahead.
>> And in those days he did eat nothing.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And when they were in it, he afterwards
hungered.
>> And afterwards he hungered. Didn't in
Luke chap uh Deuteronomy chapter 8, he
suffered them to hunger.
>> That's right.
>> That they might have their hope in God.
And what did he say?
>> That they would live by every word of
God.
>> That's right. Yes, sir.
>> Not bread alone. Right.
>> Skip down to verse 14 and read.
>> And Jesus returned in the power of the
spirit into Galilee and went out of fame
of him
>> through all the regions round about.
>> Uhhuh. And he taught in their
synagogues, being glorified of all.
>> Go ahead.
>> And he came to Nazareth, where he had
been brought up.
>> And as his custom was, he went into the
synagogue on the Sabbath day and stood
up for to read.
>> He went in the synagogue where? On the
Sabbath day.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Man, we doing the same thing Jesus did,
didn't we,
>> Bruce?
>> Yes, sir. Thank you.
>> And he stood up to read. Go ahead.
>> And there was delivered unto him the
book of the prophet Isaiah. Man, wait a
minute. He read out of the book of
Isaiah, the Old Testament.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And when he had opened the book, he
found the place where it was written.
>> Mhm.
>> The spirit of the Lord is upon me
because he had anointed me to preach the
gospel to the poor. He has sent me to
heal the brokenhearted, to preach
deliverance to the captives and
recovering of sight to the blind, to set
at liberty them that are bruised,
>> to preach the acceptable year of the
Lord.
>> Ain't that something? He taught the
people the book.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead. Amen.
>> And he closed the book.
>> And he gave it again to the minister and
sat down. And the eyes of them that were
in the synagogue were fasting on him.
>> Mhm.
>> And he began to say unto them, "This day
is this scripture fulfilled in your
ear."
>> Ain't that something? He said, "This day
is this scripture fulfilled in your
ears." because he is the one that the
spirit of the Lord was on.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Him to take the to lead us out of
captivity. That's right. The captivity
of sin. Cuz we was going to all die in
the lake of fire.
>> Jesus took that off of us.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> Now, that's why we get baptized in the
name of Jesus.
>> And we keep the law cuz we cover trying
to stay under the blood cuz if it if he
look at brother Herald, I ain't going to
make it.
>> But if he see the blood Yes sir. He
going to pass over my sins.
>> Praise God.
>> Ain't that something? Yes, sir.
>> Just like he did in the Exodus. They had
the blood over the doorpost and that was
the blood of animals, right?
>> Yes, sir. That's right.
>> But Jesus was that true lamb, people.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's the one you hiding under
>> cuz he don't want to see you cuz you
might not make it.
>> That's right.
>> But you definitely going to make it if
you what? Under the blood of Jesus.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's the one we looking for.
>> That's right.
We trying to stay under the blood.
Isaiah 61, we're going to pick it back
up at verse three. Now, back to Isaiah
61. I told you to keep a marker there.
Isaiah 61. And we're going to pick it
back at three. And this time, we're
going to read 3 to9.
Isaiah 61 verse 3. 3-9.
Go ahead, brother Bruce. Go ahead and
read it. to point unto them that mourn
in Zion, to give unto them beautyful
ashes, the oil of joy for mourning, the
garment of praise for the spirit of
heaviness,
>> that they might be called trees of
righteousness, the planting of the Lord,
>> the planting what? Of the Lord, seeds of
righteousness. Go ahead and read.
>> That he may that he might be glorified.
>> And they should build the old waste.
They should raise up the former
desolations, and they should repair the
waste cities, the desolation of many
generations,
>> and strangers shall stand and feed the
your flock.
>> And the sons of the aliens should be
your plow men and your vine dressers.
>> But only thing, you ain't going to go
oppress the stranger cuz that's what got
you into trouble in the first place.
That's right.
>> You used to oppress the stranger and the
fatherless and the widow. And that's why
we ended up in captivity. Peace, right?
>> Cuz people are like to look down on poor
folks.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Forget about the rich man. Yes,
>> sir.
>> But they want to step on poor people.
Read what Job how Job conducted himself.
>> Yes, sir.
>> If somebody was down and out, he looked
to see if he could do something.
>> Praise the Lord. That's right.
>> Ain't that something?
>> Yes, sir.
>> And we done lost sight of the things we
supposed to be doing. Go ahead and read
>> verse six. But ye shall be named the
priest of the Lord. Uh-huh.
>> Men shall call you the ministers of our
God.
>> Oh, so they you ain't going to be no
more by word no more.
>> That's right. Praise the Lord.
>> Go ahead.
>> You shall eat the riches of the
Gentiles.
>> You going to eat the riches of the
Gentile cuz the Gentiles are the one
that ran it. Right now they got all the
riches.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> And their glory shall be boast and their
glory shall ye boast yourselves.
>> Ain't that something? Just like when the
children of Israel left Egypt, didn't
they spoil the Egyptians?
>> Yes, sir.
It's going to be the same. Now you going
to spoil the nations,
>> right?
>> Go ahead.
>> For your shame, you shall have double,
and for your confusion, they shall
rejoice in their portion.
>> That's why you can look at this book,
and this is the hope.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Therefore, in their land, they shall
possess the devil.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Every last everlasting joy shall be unto
them.
>> Ain't that some everlasting
joy? Go ahead. For I, the Lord, love
judgment.
>> He said, I love judgment. Uh-huh.
>> I hate robbery.
>> He said, I hate when you rob people. Go
ahead.
>> I hate robbery for burnt offering.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And I will direct their their work in
truth.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And I will make an everlasting covenant
with them.
>> Uh-huh. Cuz he going to bring you back
into the bonds of the covenant just like
he did in their old days.
>> He ain't going to let you go right into
the land.
>> That's right.
>> You got to go back into the covenant. If
you survive that wilderness,
>> then you'll go into the landise. That's
if you still flesh and blood.
>> Yes, sir.
>> But I plan on be ruling with God. Yes,
sir.
>> That's what I plan on doing. Me, too.
>> Verse nine, what does it say?
>> And their seed shall be known among the
Gentiles.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And their offspring among the people.
>> And all that see them shall acknowledge
them.
>> They going to acknowledge you.
>> And I just said when you come around,
they ain't going to run from you no more
>> cuz they know God is with you. Go ahead
and read.
>> That they are the seed which the Lord
has blessed.
>> And that they are the seed which the
Lord hath blessed. Let's go to Jeremiah
chapter 50. Jeremiah 50. We're going to
pick it up at verse one.
Because what he got to do first, he got
to take down them nations
that had you in captivity
because you scattered into what? All the
nations. Didn't he say that?
>> Yes, sir. But that's why this world is
prepared for war because the Lord is
going to take them down in the valley of
Jehoshaphat or Armageddon.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And he going to be the one that's going
to rule with his saints.
>> That's right.
>> Jeremiah 50. We're going to pick it up
at verse one. Jeremiah 50 and what? Go
ahead and read.
>> The word of the Lord spake against
Babylon and against the land of the
called by Jeremiah the prophet.
>> Uhhuh. Declare ye among the nations and
publish and set up a standard. Publish
and conceal not. Say Babylon is taken.
Babylon is confounded. Merodak is broken
in pieces. Her idols are confounded. Her
images are broken in pieces.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For out of the north there cometh up a
nation against her, which shall make her
land desolate, and none shall dwell
therein. They shall remove, they shall
depart both man and beast.
>> Uhhuh. So that nation of the north is
talking about the Russians
>> and all her allies going to come and
deal with the west.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> In those days and in that time, said the
Lord, the children of Israel should
come. They and the children of Judah
together going and weeping, they should
go and seek the Lord their God.
>> And they going to go and what? seek the
Lord their God. Go ahead.
>> They shall ask to wait to Zion with
their faces dinner, saying, "Come and
let us join ourselves to the Lord in a
perpetual covenant that shall not be
forgotten."
>> Ain't that something?
>> Yes, sir.
>> At that time, you going to be looking
for the Lord. Go ahead and read.
>> My people has been lost sheep.
>> Their shepherds have caused them to go
astray.
>> Who caused them to go astray? The
shepherds, your preachers, they cause
you to go astray. They told you you
ain't got to keep the law.
>> That's right.
>> They trying to take your crown from
>> We saw we read when we when we o open
up. Yes, sir.
>> Blessed are they that keep the
commandments of God that they may have
right to the tree of life. Right.
>> Enter into the gates
>> and enter into the gates into the city.
Yes, sir.
>> But if you break the law, guess what?
You ain't going to have that right.
>> Right. And you going to be outside the
city. Didn't he tell you who was outside
the city?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read
>> middle of verse six.
>> Uhhuh.
>> They have turned them away on the
mountain.
>> Uhhuh.
>> They have gone from mountain to hill.
They have forgotten their resting place.
>> And mountains is represent government.
>> Yes sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And I mean all that found them have
devoured them.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And their adversaries said we offend not
because they have sinned against the
Lord.
>> Uhhuh. the habitation of justice, even
the Lord, the hope of their father.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Removed out of the midst of Babylon.
>> He said, "Now you better come out of
this Babylon doctrine." Go ahead and
read.
>> And go forth out of the land of the
called
>> and be as the goats before the flock.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For lo, I will raise and cause to come
up against Babylon.
and with me. For lo, I will raise and
cause to come up against Babylon and
assembly of great nation from the north
country.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And they shall set themselves in array
against her.
>> Ain't that so?
>> Yes sir.
>> They all these nations going to come cuz
it said what? 200 million soldiers.
>> Yes sir.
>> That's what the Bible say.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> From this she shall be taken. The errors
shall be as of mighty expert, man. None
shall return in vain.
>> Uh and go ahead.
>> And
in Cardia shall be a spoil. All the
spoil.
All that spoiled her shall be satisfied
>> because she were glad. Because she
rejoiced. Oh ye destroyers of mine
heritage.
>> Mhm. because she are grown fat as the
hepher as grass enveloped as bulls.
>> Ain't that something? Because they
prospered off you off your captivity and
now the Lord is going to deal with them.
See, he said they help forward
affliction. Didn't he say that?
>> Yes, sir. He said,
>> "Therefore, he going to make them pay."
>> That's right.
>> Let's go on. Let's go to Luke. Skip down
to verse 16. 16. Skip down to 16. We're
going to read 16 and 19. Go ahead. Cut
off the sword from Babylon and him that
handleth the sickle in the time of
harvest for fear of the oppressing
sword. They shall turn away. I mean they
should turn everyone to his people and
they shall flee everyone to his own
land.
>> Uhhuh. So everybody going to go to their
land wherever you your nativity was
>> cuz we America is just an experiment.
North America and all that. They going
to go back to where they originally
from. Yes sir. Go ahead and read.
>> Israel is a scattered sheep.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The lions have driven him away.
>> Go ahead.
>> First, the king of Assyria has devou him
>> cuz the Assyrians was the one that took
us the the the northern kingdom out. Go
ahead and read.
>> And last, this Nebuchadnezzar,
king of Babylon, has broken his bone.
>> Uh-huh. So, Nebuchadnezzar took out
Judah. Go ahead and read. Therefore,
thus said the Lord of hosts, the God of
Israel, behold, I will punish the king
of Babylon in his land, as I have
punished the king of Assyria,
>> and I will bring Israel again to his
habitation,
>> and he shall feed on on Caramel and
Bashan, and his soul shall be satisfied
upon Mount Ephilead.
Uh-huh. So, he going to bring you back
to the land that he originally gave to
you, the land of Canaan. Let's go to
Luke 21 and let's see the time line when
this going to happen. Luke 21 and we're
going to pick it up at verse 25. Luke 21
and 25.
25- 28.
Because he said in verse 24, you going
to be led away captive into
>> time
>> all nations and you gonna be there until
the times of the Gentiles. Right
>> now he took it right to the his second
coming. Verse 25, what does it say?
>> And there shall be signs in the sun and
in the moon and in the stars and upon
the earth, distress of nations with
perplexity, the sea and the waves
roaring.
>> Uh-huh. So it's going to be the size of
the sun and moon. We going to see it
later. He ma Matthew going to get more
specific about it. But go ahead and
read.
>> Men's hearts fell in them for fear and
for looking after those things which are
coming on the earth.
>> For the powers of heaven should be
shaken.
>> Cuz he going to shake the heavens.
>> Yes sir.
>> Other scriptures tell you he going to
shake the ball like the earth like a
ball.
>> Yes sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And then shall they see the son of man
coming in a cloud with power and great
glory.
>> Uhhuh. And when these things begin to
come to pass, then look up
>> and lift up your head
>> for your redemption drawth nigh.
>> He said, then look up for your
redemption draws n just like they looked
upon that serpent upon the stick. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And those who looked up that had the
faith was healed, wasn't they?
>> Yes, sir.
>> It's going to be the same way in the
last days. Let's go to Re Revelation
chapter 6. Revelation chapter 6, we're
going to pick it up at verse 12.
Revelation 6. All these things got to
come because this is the delivery. This
is the restoration of Israel. The
restoration. We saw he was put into
captivity. Right
>> now, we seeing Israel being restored.
Revelation 6 and verse 12. And we going
to see the things happening before they
are res restored.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Verse 12. Revelation 6 and2. Go ahead
and read.
>> And I beheld when he had opened the
sixth seal, and lo, there was a great
earthquake, and the sun became black as
sackcloth of hair, and the moon became
as blood. Now, we said, we seen the
signs in the heavens, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> The sun and the moon, right?
>> Because that's what Luke said. Now,
Revelation, the writer of Revelations
get specific about Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And the stars of heaven fell upon the
earth.
>> Uhhuh. Even as the fig tree castes her
untimely figs, when she is shaken of a
mighty wind.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the heaven departed as a scroll when
it is rolled together. And every
mountain and island was moved out of
their places.
>> And the kings of the earth and the great
men and the rich men and the chief
captains and the mighty men and every
bond man and every free man hid
themselves in the dens and in the rocks
of the mountains.
>> Why they hiding themselves? Cuz
everybody love Jesus.
Why they hiding? Because they've been
lying on the Lord all this time. And now
it's payoff time.
>> Go ahead and read
>> 16. And said to the mountains and rocks,
"Fall on us and hide us from the face of
him that sitting on the throne and from
the wrath of the lamb."
>> That's going to be something.
>> You you you that scared, but you so
wicked that you going to hide instead of
>> saying, "The Lord saved me." Ain't that
something? Wow.
>> Verse 17.
>> For the great day of his wrath is come
and who shall be able to stand?
>> Read writing of Revelation 7 and one.
Because before he pour out his wrath, he
going to seal his 144,000 out of the 12
tribes of Israel. Yes, sir.
>> Before he pour out his wrath. Verse one.
Revelation 7 and 1. Go ahead and read.
And after these things, I saw four
angels standing on the four corners of
the earth, holding the four winds of the
earth, that the wind should not blow on
the earth, nor on the sea, nor on any
tree.
>> Ain't that something?
>> So the Lord got four angels holding back
the nations.
>> Just think if he didn't hold them, they
ready to fight now. But the Lord is the
one holding back this thing until things
happen that has to happen.
>> Cuz they ready to fight any debt.
>> They ready to start pushing buttons,
people.
>> But the Lord is the one controlling this
thing.
>> Yes, sir. That's right.
>> Cuz he said if he didn't, no flesh would
be saved. Right.
>> That's right.
>> But for the elect's sake, he going to
save. Stop it. Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read
>> verse two. And I saw another angel
ascending from the east having a seal of
the living God. And he cried with a loud
voice to the four angels to whom it was
given to hurt the earth and the sea,
>> saying, "Hurt not the earth, neither the
sea, nor the trees, till we have sealed
the service of our God in their
forehead."
>> Uhhuh. Those in that particular area
around where the beast and false prophet
going to be, that's in Jerusalem. Yes,
sir.
>> This these are ones he going to seal out
of the 12 tribes of Israel. Remember the
church is going to be in the wilderness
cuz they saw when they saw the
abominations of desolation stand in the
holy place. They flee to the place of
safety. Yes sir.
>> So that the church is in the wilderness.
>> The remnant is the ones that's going
that he going to seal out of the 12
tribes of Israel.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> I heard the number of them which was
sealed
>> and that was sealed inund,000
of all the tribes of the children of
Israel.
>> Of all the tribes of what? the children
of Israel. Not that's why you ask them
people that knock on your door. Boom,
boom, boom, boom.
>> They always talking about the 144,000.
But they won't read out of the tribes of
the children of Israel. You are you an
Israelite? Oh, no. No.
Then what are you talking about? Right.
Skip down to verse nine and read. That's
just something to think about.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Did I say verse nine?
>> Yeah. And read.
>> Yeah. Skip down to verse nine. Go ahead.
>> After this, I beheld, and lo, a great
multitude, which no man could count, of
all nations,
>> all nations
>> and kindred
>> and people and tongues
>> stood before the throne and before the
lamb clothed with white robes and palms
in their hands.
>> All nations,
all nations.
How come they don't read that? Them
people that be dressed in costumes on
the street,
>> they won't read that, will they?
>> No. No sir.
>> All nations. Skip down to verse 13 and
read.
>> And one of the elders answered, saying
unto me, What are these which are raided
in white robes,
>> and which came they? And I said unto
him, Sir, thou knowest. And he said to
me, "These are they which came out of
great tribulation."
>> These are they that came out of what?
Great tribulation. Go ahead and read.
>> And have washed their robes and made
them white in the blood of the lamb.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Therefore are they before the throne of
God, and serve him day and night in his
temple, and he that siteth on the throne
shall dwell among them.
>> Ain't that something? Just like when in
Exodus, he going to have a mixed
multitude when in the last days.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> They shall hunger no more.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Neither thirst anymore. Neither should
the sun light on them, nor any heat.
>> Mhm.
>> For the lamb which is in the midst of
the throne shall feed them, and shall
lead them unto living unto living
fountains of water.
>> Oh, in other words, he going to teach
them.
>> Yes, sir. Go ahead.
>> And God should wipe away all tears from
their eyes.
>> And he going to wipe away all tears from
their eyes. Isaiah 49, we're going to
pick it up at verse 8. Isaiah 49 and 8.
Isaiah 49 and we going to pick it up at
verse 8.
That's something. The Lord going to do
all this for his people.
>> Yes, sir. Yes.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Isaiah 49 and verse 8. Go ahead and
read. Thus said the Lord,
in an acceptable time have I heard thee,
>> and in a day of salvation have I helped
thee, and I will preserve thee, and give
thee for a covenant of the people, to
establish the earth, to cause to inherit
the desolate heritage.
>> Mhm.
>> That thou mayest say to the prisoners,
go forth.
>> And he going to say to the prisoners, go
forth. Go ahead.
>> That are in darkness.
>> Uhhuh. Show yourself.
>> They shall feed in the waves, and their
pastures shall be in all high places.
>> They shall not hunger, nor thirst.
Neither shall the heat nor sun smite
them.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For he that has mercy on them shall lead
them, even by the springs of water
should he guide them.
>> Man, that sound like Revelation, ain't
it?
>> Yes, sir. Exactly.
>> That's Revelation 7.
>> That's right.
>> It was written in the Old Testament.
>> Yes, sir. That's right. Go ahead and
read.
>> And I will make all my mountains a way,
and my highways shall be exalted.
>> Behold, these shall come from far, and
lo, these from the north and from the
west, and these from the land of sa
Simon.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Sing, O heavens, and be joyful, O earth,
and break forth into singing, O
mountains, for the Lord hath comforted
his people, and will have mercy upon his
afflicted. He going to have mercy upon
what? The afflicted.
He going to have mercy upon the
afflicted.
Let's go on to Joel chapter 3. Joel
chapter 3 and we're going to pick it up
at verse one. We getting close to the
end. Joel chapter 3 and we're going to
pick it up at verse one.
Joel chapter 3 and we're going to pick
it up at verse one.
Go ahead and read.
>> For behold, in those days and in that
time when I shall bring again the
captivity of Judah and Jerusalem,
>> I will also gather all nations and will
bring them down into the valley of
Jehoshaphat.
>> He said, I'm going to bring them down to
the valley of Jehoshaphat. That's where
Jehovah going to judge. Go ahead and
read.
>> And I will plead with them.
>> Uh-huh. Therefore, my people and for my
heritage Israel,
>> he said, I'm going to plead with them
for my people, my heritage, Israel. So,
Brother Bruce, I got a question to ask
you.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Did this happen in 1948?
>> Not Not according to the Bible.
>> Not according to the Bible. Right. Go
ahead.
>> Could I start over verse two?
>> Verse two.
>> I will also gather all nations. It will
bring them down into the valley of
Jehoshaphat and will plead with them
there for my people and for my hedge
Israel whom they have scattered among
the nations
>> whom they have scattered among the
nations
>> and parted my land.
>> Cuz all nations had a party this day. Go
ahead and read.
And they have cast lot and they have
cast lots for my people and have given a
boy for an harlot and sold a girl for
wine that they might drink.
>> Ain't that something? You were sold like
you was a medium of exchange. Go ahead
and read.
>> Yay. And what have ye to do with me, oh
Tyrie and Zylon, and all the coast of
Philistine?
Will ye I mean Palestine? Will ye
renderth me a recompense?
>> And if ye recompense me swiftly and
speedily, will I return your recompense
upon your own head?
>> Uh, if you try to repay me, I'mma turn
it right on your head. Go ahead and
read.
>> Because ye have taken my silver and my
gold, and have carried into your temples
my goodly, pleasant things.
>> Uh-huh. Cuz they just when they
destroyed Solomon's temple, it was
magnificant, wasn't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead and read. The children also of
Judah and the children of Jerusalem have
ye sold unto the Grecians
>> that ye might remove them far from their
borders.
>> Ain't that the ain't the Americas and
the islands and all that that's far from
the borders of Jerusalem.
>> That's right.
>> So the Lord, he say he going to repay
them for this.
>> That's right.
>> Read verse seven. Behold, I will raise
them out of the place whether ye have
sold them
>> and will return your recompense upon
your own head.
>> He said, I'm going to repay you for
this. Skip down to verse N and read.
>> Proclaim ye this among the Gentiles.
>> Prepare war. Wake up the mighty men. Let
all the men of war draw near. Let them
come up.
>> Let them come up. Let all them prepare
for war.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You got to read verse 10. This is why
they cutting your social programs. Read
this verse 10.
>> Beat your plowshares into swords.
>> Beat your plowshares, your economic
programs that's supposed to help people.
Beat them into what? Swords.
>> Go ahead.
>> And your pruning hooks into spear. And
your pruning hooks fade to help people
into what? Spears. That's why all these
nations is preparing for war.
>> They are. They cutting programs all over
the world
>> and building nothing but m met military
stuff.
>> Yes, that's right.
>> I had to Bruce got hit me in the back.
>> Militious.
>> They they going malicious on
>> verse 10. Read it again.
>> Okay.
>> Beat your plow shears into sword.
>> Uh-huh. in your pruning hooks and the
spears.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Let the weak say I'm strong.
>> Now the weak nations saying they strong
a sir
>> because everybody trying to get these
weapons and trying to look strong. Skip
down to verse 12 and read 12- 16. Go
ahead.
>> Let the heathens be awake. Let the
heathens be waken
>> and come up to the valley of
Jehoshaphat.
>> They all going to come down to the
valley of Jehoshaphat. Go ahead. For
there will I sit to judge all the
heathen round about.
>> Go ahead.
>> Put ye in the sickle,
>> for the harvest is ripe. Come ye,
>> get down. Come ye, get you down, for the
press is full, the fats overflow, for
their wickedness is great.
>> For their wickedness is great. Go ahead.
>> Multitudes. Multitudes in the valley of
decision. They ain't nothing going to be
nothing but military people down there.
Go ahead and read.
>> For the day of the Lord is near in the
valley of decision
>> and near in the valley of decision. Go
ahead.
>> The sun and the moon should be darkened.
>> We saw Matthew talk about that. Right.
Go ahead and read.
>> And the stars shall withdraw their
shine.
>> And the stars going to bring other
scriptures say the stars going to fall,
ain't there?
>> That's right.
>> So ain't no need of you going on Mars
and stuff. They ain't going to be no
place to be. That's
>> the Lord going to deal with that.
>> What else they doing?
>> Go ahead and read.
>> The Lord also shall roar out of Zion and
utter his voice from Jerusalem and the
heavens and the earth shall shake.
>> But the Lord will be the hope of his
people and the strength of the children
of Israel
>> and the strength of the children of
Israel. Matthew 24. We're going to move
quickly. We're going to get on out of
here so y'all can get ready for the
feast tomorrow.
>> Matthew 24. We're going to pick it up at
verse 27.
Matthew 24 and we're going to pick it up
at verse 27.
Matthew 24 and 27. Then we going to skip
to 29.
Okay, go ahead.
>> For as the lightning cometh out of the
east and shineth even unto the west, so
shall also the coming of the son of man
be.
>> So he ain't going to sneak up on the
earth. No, sir. Like you see lightning
in the sky, that's the way the Lord's
second coming going to be. Skip down to
verse 29 and read.
>> Immediately after the tribulation of
those days should the sun be darkened
and the moon shall not give her light.
>> Oh, that's the sign again. Go ahead.
>> And the stars shall fall from heaven.
>> And the powers of the heavens shall be
shaken.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And then shall appear the sign of the
son of man. And then shall And then
shall appear thus sign of the son of man
in heaven. And then shall all the tribes
of the earth mourn,
>> and they shall see the son of man coming
in the clouds of heaven with power and
great glory.
>> And he ain't talking about rapturing off
nobody, is it?
>> No, sir.
>> Immediately after the tribulation, oh
days, you going to see the sign of the
son of man coming in heaven. You read
31. And he shall send his angels with a
great sound of a trumpet, and they shall
gather together his elect from the four
winds from one end of heaven to the
other.
>> Uh-huh. That's one end of the earth to
the other. Let's go to Isaiah 27. And
we're going to pick it up at verse 12.
Isaiah 27 and 12. Isaiah 27. We're just
going to read 12 and 13.
Isaiah 27 and we're going to pick it up
at verse 12.
Go ahead and read it when you get it,
brothers.
Isaiah 27 and 12.
Go ahead and read And it shall come to
pass in that day that the Lord shall
beat off from the channel of the river
unto the stream of Egypt,
>> and ye shall be gathered one by one all
ye children of Israel.
>> Oh, so it's written in the Old
Testament. Yes, sir.
>> You going to be gathered one by one, oh
children of Israel. Verse 13.
>> And it shall come to pass in that day
>> that the great trumpet shall be blown.
>> That's the seventh trumpet. Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead. And they shall come which were
ready to perish into the land of
Assyria.
>> Mhm.
>> And the outcast in the land of Egypt.
>> Uhhuh. Cuz Israel was scattered mostly
among hell.
>> Yes, sir.
>> There's only a few of us among the
Gentiles.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> They should worship the Lord in the holy
mountain
>> at Jerusalem.
>> At Jerusalem. Cuz the Lord going to be
there. That's where he going to rule
from. Zechariah chapter 2. And we're
going to pick it up at verse one.
Zechariah 2 and 1.
the book of Zechariah 2 and we're going
to pick it up at verse one. We looking
at the restoration of Israel now.
Zechariah 2 and we're going to pick it
up at verse one.
And when you get it,
go ahead and read. I lifted up mine eyes
again and looked and behold a man with a
measuring line in his hand. Then said I,
whether goest thou? And he said unto me
to measure Jerusalem, to see what is the
breadth thereof, and what is the lint
thereof. And behold, the angel that
talked with me went forth. And another
angel went out to meet him.
>> Go ahead.
>> And said unto him, "Run, speak to this
young man, saying, Jerusalem should be
inhabited as towns without walls, for
the multitude of men and cattle
therein."
>> Uh-huh. So you ain't going to need no
the the things you had to set up before,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> The Lord is the one that's going to be
fighting for you. Go ahead and read.
>> Fine. For I said the Lord will be unto
her a wall of fire round about.
>> The Lord is going to be the one
protecting you.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You ain't going to have to have all
these armies and all that. Go ahead.
>> And will be the glory in the midst of
her.
>> Go ahead.
>> Ho ho. Come forth and flee from the land
of the north. The Lord said the Lord.
For I have spread you abroad as the four
winds of the heaven, sayeth the Lord.
>> Uhhuh. So I spread you abroad as the
four winds of heaven. But I'm going to
deliver you. Verse seven.
>> Deliver thyself, O Zion, that dwelleth
with the daughter of Babylon.
>> What dwelleth what? The daughters of
Babylon. Go ahead and read.
>> For thus sayeth the Lord of hosts, after
the glory had he sent me into unto the
nations which spoiled you.
>> Uhhuh. That's talking about Jesus.
That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> For he that touches you touches the
apple of his eye.
>> Touches the apple of who? The father's
eye. The apple of the father's eye.
>> Verse nine.
>> For behold, I will shake my hand upon
them.
>> And they shall be a spoil to their
servants,
>> and ye shall know that the Lord of hosts
has sent me.
>> Go ahead. Sing and rejoice, oh daughter
of Zion, for lo, I come and I will dwell
in the midst of thee, said the Lord.
>> I'm going to dwell in the midst of you,
said the Lord. So is the Lord dwelling
in the midst of these people now?
>> No, sir.
>> So you talking something in the future.
Amen.
>> That's right. Go ahead and read verse
11. And many nations shall be joined to
the Lord in that day.
>> What? Many nations.
>> That's right. Cuz the Lord in the
business of saving all whosoever will.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And shall be my people, and I will dwell
in the midst of thee.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And thou shall know that the Lord of
hosts has sent me unto thee.
>> Go ahead. Verse 12.
>> And the Lord shall inherit Judah, his
portion, and the holy land, and shall
choose Jerusalem again.
>> Now, let's go to Zechariah chapter 8.
And we g and we got three more places
after they short. Zechariah 8 and we're
going to pick it up at verse one.
Zechariah 8 and one. Now look at the
conditions
that is going to be Jerusalem going to
be in when the Lord return. Zechariah 8
and1. What it say again? The word of the
Lord of hosts came to me saying, "Thus
said the Lord of hosts,
>> I was jealous for Zion with great
jealousy, and I was jealous for her with
great fury."
>> Thus said the Lord, I am returned unto
Zion.
>> He said, "What? I am returned unto
Zion."
>> Go ahead.
>> And will dwell in the midst of
Jerusalem.
>> Hey, the Lord going to dwell in
Jerusalem. Yes, he is. Go ahead. And
Jerusalem shall be called a city of
truth.
>> Oh man, ain't going to be no more pride
parades in Jerusalem.
>> No, sir.
>> And Tel Aviv and all of that.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And the mountain of the Lord of hosts,
the holy mountain.
the holy mountain. Go ahead and read.
Thus said the Lord of hosts, "There
shall yet all men and all women dwell in
the street of the streets of Jerusalem,
and every man with his staff his hand
for burriade." In his hand for burriade.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And the streets of the city shall be
full of boys and girls playing in the
streets thereof.
>> Oh, so it ain't going to be no more uh
suicide bombings and all that type of
stuff. Go ahead and read. Thus said the
Lord of hosts.
>> Uhhuh.
>> If it be marvelous in the eyes of the
remnants of this people in these days,
should it also be marvelous in mine
eyes, said the Lord of Hosts.
>> Uh-huh. To It's going to be marvelous
even in the Lord's eyes. Yes,
>> sir.
>> Because there hasn't been no peace.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Thus said the Lord of hosts.
>> Behold, I will save my people from the
east country and from the west country.
>> That's us. We from the west country.
That's why we face toward Jerusalem.
Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> And I will bring them and they shall
dwell in the midst of Jerusalem.
>> And they shall be my people and I will
be their God in truth and righteousness.
>> When in truth and in righteousness.
>> Go ahead. Thus said the Lord of hosts,
"Let your hands be strong, ye that hear
in these days these words by the mouth
of the prophets, which were in the day
that the foundation of the house of the
Lord of hosts was laid, that the temple
might be built."
>> Uhhuh. For before these days, there were
no hire for men,
>> nor any hire for beasts, neither were
there any beast to him that went out or
came in because of their affliction.
>> Uh-huh. Because the man of sin was in
there, and he was killing all those that
kept the commandments of God and the
faith of Jesus. Go ahead and read.
>> So I said, all men, everyone against his
name.
>> Uh-huh. But
now
I
will not be unto the residue of this
people as in the former day, said the
Lord of hosts.
>> Verse 12.
>> For the seed shall be prosperous. The
vine shall give her fruit
>> and the ground shall give her increase.
>> Wait, now he going back to where he said
he was going to bless you, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead. and the heavens shall give her
their due.
>> Oh, so he going to give you your rain
and all that. Go ahead.
>> And I will cause the remnant of their
people to possess all these things.
>> Then he said, I'm going to call the
remnant of people that possess, skip
down to verse 20 and read 20 to 23. What
it said?
>> Thus said the Lord of hosts, it shall
yet come to pass that there shall come
people and the inhabitants of many
cities.
>> Uhhuh.
and the inhabitants of one city should
go to another, saying, "Let us go
speedily to pray before the Lord, and to
seek the Lord of hosts. I will go also."
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. Many people and strong nations
should come to seek the Lord of hosts in
Jerusalem, and to pray before the Lord.
>> So, the whole world is going to go and
pray before the Lord. Go ahead.
>> 23. Thus said the Lord of hosts, in
those days it should come to pass that
10 men should take hold out of all
languages of the nations, even shall
take hold of the skirt of him that is a
Jew, saying, "We will go with you, for
we have heard that God is with you."
>> Ain't that so? They going to hang on to
you because they know salvation is of
the Jews. Yes, sir.
>> Isaiah 65 and we're going to pick it up
at verse 9. Isaiah 65 and9. We got two
more places. Isaiah 65 and we're going
to pick it up at verse 9.
Isaiah 65 and 9.
Then we're going to skip to 17. Isaiah
65. We're going to pick it up at verse
9.
And when you get it, Brother Bruce, go
ahead and read.
And I will bring forth a seed out of
Jacob and out of Judah, an inheritor of
my mountain,
>> and mine elect shall inherit it.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And my servants shall dwell there.
>> And my servant, that's mountain is
government. And my servants shall dwell
there. Skip down to 17 and read.
For behold, I create new heavens and a
new earth, and the former shall not be
remembered, nor come into mine.
>> Cuz he going to create new conditions.
That's what he mean by create a new
heavens and a new earth.
>> Go ahead.
>> But be ye glad and rejoice forever in
that which I create.
>> For behold, I create Jerusalem
a rejoicing in her people of joy.
>> That's why it's going to be called new.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Because what? It ain't happening. That's
right.
>> Like that before. Go ahead.
>> And I will rejoice in Jerusalem and joy
my people.
>> And the voice of weeping shall be no
more heard in them,
>> nor the voice of crying.
>> Uhhuh.
>> There shall be no more this in infinite
days.
>> Nor an old man that has not filled his
day.
>> For the child should die 100 years old.
>> That's how we know this gonna be Jesus'
kingdom. Because ain't no more death in
the father's kingdom. He said a child if
you die at a 100 you going to be like a
child cuz the Lord going to extend the
years like he did in the days of uh
>> what's that Methusela and
>> go ahead and read
>> but the sinner being 100 years old shall
be a cursed
>> if you don't get it right by 100 you
will be a curse.
>> Yes sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And they shall build houses and inhabit
them. And they shall plant vineyards and
eat the fruit of them.
>> Go ahead, digle the blessings now, sir.
Go ahead and read.
>> They shall not build in another inhabit.
>> They shall not plant in another eat.
>> For as the days of a tree are the days
of my people.
>> Uhhuh. You know, a tree live a long
time, don't it? Go ahead.
>> And my elect shall long enjoy the work
of their hand.
>> Uhhuh.
>> They shall not labor in vain.
>> Nor bring forth for trouble.
>> Uhhuh. For they are the seed of the
blessed of the Lord and their offspring
with them.
>> Oh, he going to bless your children and
everything. Go ahead.
>> And it shall come to pass that before
they call, I will answer.
>> Oh, before you even ask anything.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He going to answer you already. Go ahead
and read.
>> And will and while they are yet
speaking, I will hear.
>> And I ain't going to hear you. Ain't
going to turn his back on you no more
because you going to be righteous. You
going to be commandments of God. Go
ahead.
>> Verse 25. The wolf and the lamb shall
feed together.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the lion
>> shall eat straw like the bullock.
>> So we we don't see that going on now, do
we?
>> But we'll see that when the Lord come
back. Go ahead.
>> And thus shall be the serpent's meat.
>> So snakes ain't going to be eating
people.
>> That's right.
>> Or other animals. Go ahead.
>> They shall not hurt nor destroy in all
my holy mountain.
>> Uh-huh. Now, let's go to Acts. Acts
chapter one,
>> and we got one more place after that.
Acts chapter 1, and we're going to pick
it up at verse 6. We just going to read
6 and 7. Cuz when Jesus rose from the
dead,
they thought he was going to restore the
kingdom at the time of the apostles.
But let's see what Jesus told them. Acts
chapter 1, we're going to read verse 6.
This is after the resurrection of Jesus.
And he was with the with him speaking
what? 40 days things pertaining to the
kingdom of God.
>> Yes sir.
>> And let's see what happened. Verse six.
When they therefore was come together,
they asked of him, saying, Lord, will
thou at this time restore again the
kingdom to Israel.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he said unto them, it is not for you
to know the times or the seasons which
the father has put in his own power.
>> Huh? So he said, "It ain't for you to
know the times or the seasons."
>> That's right.
>> But the father had put in his own times.
So they thought he was going to bring it
right then.
>> That's right.
>> But let's go to Leviticus chapter 26.
Leviticus chapter 26. Cuz the Moses
called it even in the old book.
In fact, when Moses put down the pen, it
was over. That's right.
>> He called the end from the beginning.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Which was dictated by the Lord.
Leviticus 26. We're going to pick it up
at verse 40.
>> Leviticus 26. And we going to read 40 to
46. And this the last place. And y'all
can go take a nice deep breath. Is over.
Leviticus 26. And we're going to pick it
up at verse 40. What it say? If they
should confess their iniquity in the
iniquities of their fathers with their
trespass which they trespass against me
>> and that also they have walked contrary
unto me.
>> He said what if you confess that right?
Yes sir.
>> Cuz that starts everything confessions.
Go ahead and read.
>> And that I also have walked contrary
unto them
>> and have brought them into the land of
their enemies.
>> If then their uncircumcised heart be
humbled.
>> If they what uncircumcised heart be
what? Humble.
>> Humble. So he trying to humble us. Go
ahead and read.
>> And they then accept of the punishment
of their iniquity.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Then will I remember my covenant with
Jacob.
>> Then I'm going to remember my covenant
that I made with Jacob.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And also my covenant with Isaac.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And also my covenant with Abraham.
>> Would I remember?
>> I will remember the land.
>> And I'm going to remember the land. Go
ahead and read. The land also shall be
left of them
>> and she'll enjoy her Sabbath
>> while she lieth desolate without them.
>> Uhhuh. Ain't the land still enjoying her
Sabbath?
>> The people over there thinking they the
people of God, don't they? Yes, sir.
>> They keep the Sabbath day, don't they?
Yes, sir.
>> Even though you ain't there. That's what
he mean by desolate. Yes, sir.
>> It's empty to the Lord even though
somebody else is there. That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And they shall accept of the punishment
of their iniquity.
>> Uhhuh. Because even because they despise
my judgment and because their soul
afforded my statute.
>> Mhm.
>> And yet for all that when they be in the
land of their enemies.
>> And when you be in the land of what? Of
your enemies. Go ahead.
>> I will not cast them away.
>> Now I'm not going to cast you away.
Ain't that so? Cuz these people, all
these people tried to exterminate us.
They starting to They trying to
exterminate even your brothers over
there. That's right.
>> Among Hell. Yes, sir. Go ahead and read.
>> Neither will I Neither will I abhoord
them.
>> Neither will I abhord them
>> to destroy them utterly and to break my
covenant with them.
>> For I am the Lord their God.
>> I am the Lord their God. Thank God the
Lord made the covenant with Abraham and
Isaac and Jacob.
>> Yes, sir.
>> We will be like Sodom and Gomorrah
people. We be gone.
>> That's right.
>> Cuz the Lord is a covenant God.
>> Right. That's right.
>> He keep his word. Go ahead.
>> Verse 45. But I will not for their sake
remember the covenant of their ancestors
whom I brought forth out of the land of
Egypt and the sight of the heathen that
I might be their God. I am the Lord.
>> Go ahead.
>> These are the statutes and judgment and
laws which the Lord made.
>> You know what? Read 45 one more time.
Read 45 one more time. Go ahead. But I
will for their sakes
>> But I will for their sakes
>> remember the covenant of their
ancestors.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Whom I brought forth out of the land of
Egypt
>> in the sight of the heathen that I might
be their God. I am the Lord.
>> Go ahead. These are the statutes and
judgments and laws which the Lord made
between him
and the children of Israel and Mount Si
by the hand of Moses.
>> Ain't that something? Yes,
>> sir.
>> So, the Lord said we just saw the
destruction and the restoration of
Israel.
And I thank you for your time.